+1 514 546 3111

ASHISH KANWAR as

ashishkanwar.com ashishthakurg13@gmail.com



SOFTWARE ENGINEER

SUMMARY

I love building new things from scratch and that is what I have been doing professionally for over 5 years. I am a tinkerer (DIY crafts, remote cars, LEGO) and that has always made me believe that I can build anything I desire. I am very passionate about writing code and bringing life-changing products to life. I am an outdoor person and I enjoy riding a bike or skiing downhill during winter.

SKILLS

- JavaScript (ES6+)
- Typescript
- React Redux
- Golang

- PHP
- SQL/NoSQL
- HTML & (S)CSS
- Continuous Integration
- UI/UX
- Containerization
- Agile
- Linux/Ubuntu

EXPERIENCE

ART OF WHERE

Software Engineer (2018 - present)

- Built a new website with react-redux for a new subsidiary company (artfabrics.com)
- Develop and maintain an online store and an online 3D design lab (artofwhere.com)
- Helped decouple a monolith into smaller, manageable PHP composer packages
- Develop and maintain a complex in house manufacturing management software
- Increased code coverage by 10% using Codeception and Jest testing frameworks.

70MATO

Software Engineer (2015 - 2018)

- Built Zomato's new product (Zomato Gold) contributing toward both tech and product development
- Implemented PWA (Progressive Web App) for Zomato's mobile web in a small team of five using React and Redux
- Implemented Google's AMP for Zomato's mobile web. This got featured on Google's blog post.
- Worked on Zomato's web platform frequently pushing new features live (front end and back end)
- Extensively worked on RESTful APIs for mobile apps (IOS / Android)
- Made various internal tools for the ad sales team helping the team derive more revenue
- Interviewed prospective employees and mentored junior software developers on the team

EDUCATION

MS IN SOFTWARE AND OUALITY SYSTEMS

Concordia University (2018 - 2020)

BS IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Punjab Technical University (2011 - 2015)